<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Anubhav Choudhary</title><link>https://deprov447.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Anubhav Choudhary</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 12:40:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deprov447.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LFX Mentorship For Me</title><link>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/lfx/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 12:40:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/lfx/</guid><description>LFX Mentorship For Me Hi everyone, I recently completed my LFX Mentorship project. I was a mentee for the LFXM summer term of 2022 at Pixie, a CNCF sandbox project donated by The New Relic.
In this blog, I will be sharing my experience of mentorship. (TLDR; just awesome, one-of-a-kind experience &amp;lt;3)
If you&amp;rsquo;re also applying for this (which every open-source newbie should), or have a doubt, feel free to drop me a message.</description></item><item><title>SoK Final Update</title><link>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/sok-final/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:53:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/sok-final/</guid><description>Season of KDE 2021 Final Update Hello again everyone, I wrote my last update related to Season of KDE in January, and now is the time for the final update. I am sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t write blogs in between. The 3 months passed by like at supersonic speed.
So I was selected to work on Calamares project under Adriaan de Groot. Most of my work revolved around the functionality of sending the installation logs to paste server online.</description></item><item><title>Kernel Based Virtualization</title><link>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/kvm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 18:50:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/kvm/</guid><description>Kernel Based Virtualization KVM (Kernel-based Virtual Machine) is an open source, full virtualization solution for x86 hardwares containing virtualization extensions. It is a hypervisor built into the Linux kernel and unlike regular VM players like Virtualbox and VMware which use emulation, KVM uses CPU extensions for hardware assisted virtualization via a kernel module (thats the secret for that blazing speed). Each virtual machine has private virtualized hardware: a network card, disk, graphics adapter and all the peripherals.</description></item><item><title>Linux Experience After 10 Months</title><link>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/linux-after-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 14:18:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://deprov447.github.io/posts/linux-after-10/</guid><description>Linux Experience After 10 Months Its been around 10 months of me using Linux as my primary OS. I bought my laptop on Jan 1st, 2020 (yes :D) and today its Oct 5th (technically been 9 months, but okay). So let me share my experience regarding the same.
Starting / Booting Up So immediately after getting my laptop, I downloaded an Ubuntu 18.04 LTS ISO image and flashed it on a pen drive.</description></item></channel></rss>